
var quiz = {
    "JS": [
        {
            "id": 1,
            "question": "It is often a straightforward proposition to determine the performance of a system as a function of its parameters.",
            "options": [
                {
                    "a" : "Large versus systems",
                    "b" : "Nonlinear versus linear",
                    "c" : "Design",
                    "d" : "Sensitivity analysis",
                    "e" : "None of the above",
                }
            ],
            "answer": "Design",
            "score": 0,
            "status": ""
        },
        {
            "id": 2,
            "question": "This is the discrepancy between an exact value and some approximation to it.",
            "options": [
                {
                    "a" : "Round-off errors",
                    "b" : "Total numerical error",
                    "c" : "Truncation error",
                    "d" : "Approximation error",
                    "e" : "None of the above",
                }
            ],
            "answer": "Approximation error",
            "score": 0,
            "status": ""
        },
        {
            "id": 3,
            "question": "This is the summation of the truncation and round-off errors.",
            "options": [
                {
                    "a" : "Round-off errors",
                    "b" : "Total numerical error",
                    "c" : "Truncation error",
                    "d" : "Approximation error",
                    "e" : "None of the above",
                }
            ],
            "answer": "Total numerical error”",
            "score": 0,
            "status": ""
        },
        {
            "id": 4,
            "question": "_________ refers to how closely a computed or measured value agrees with the true value.",
            "options": [
                {
                    "a" : "Precision",
                    "b" : "True value",
                    "c" : "Accuracy",
                    "d" : "Round-off errors",
                    "e" : "None of the above",
                }
            ],
            "answer": "Accuracy",
            "score": 0,
            "status": ""
        },
        {
            "id": 5,
            "question": "It is a special type of software that allows the user to enter and perform calculations on rows and columns of data.",
            "options": [
                {
                    "a" : "Excel",
                    "b" : "Matlab",
                    "c" : "Mathcad",
                    "d" : "Gitlab",
                    "e" : "None of the above",
                }
            ],
            "answer": "Excel",
            "score": 0,
            "status": ""
        },
        {
            "id": 6,
            "question": "If the true value of a measurement is 10.9 cm and the approximate value is 10.7 cm, what is the true error?",
            "options": [
                {
                    "a" : "0.2 cm",
                    "b" : "1.8 cm",
                    "c" : "0.2 %",
                    "d" : "1.8 %",
                    "e" : "None of the above",
                }
            ],
            "answer": "0.2 cm",
            "score": 0,
            "status": ""
        },
        {
            "id": 7,
            "question":  "If the true value of a measurement is 10.9 cm and the approximate value is 10.7 cm, what is the true relative error?",
            "options": [
                {
                    "a" : "0.2 cm",
                    "b" : "1.8 cm",
                    "c" : "0.2 %",
                    "d" : "1.8 %",
                    "e" : "None of the above",
                }
            ],
            "answer": "1.8 %",
            "score": 0,
            "status": ""
        },
        {
            "id": 8,
            "question": "Solving the function f(x)=4x3-15x2+17x+6 using the Newton-Raphson method with a starting value of x = 0, the first iteration yields a value of x equal to:",
            "options": [
                {
                    "a" : "0.3529",
                    "b" : "- 0.3529",
                    "c" : "6",
                    "d" : "17",
                    "e" : "None of the above",
                }
            ],
            "answer": "6",
            "score": 0,
            "status": ""
        },
        {
            "id": 9,
            "question": "Using Bairstow’s method to solve the roots of the equation f(x) = x^4 - x - 10 with starting values r = 0.1 and s = 0.1, the first iteration yields:",
            "options": [
                {
                    "a" : "r = 1.251, s = 0.113",
                    "b" : "r = - 3.145, s = 4.678",
                    "c" : "r = 1.315, s = 5.278",
                    "d" : "r = - 7.364, s = 13.579",
                    "e" : "None of the above",
                }
            ],
            "answer": "r = - 7.364, s = 13.579",
            "score": 0,
            "status": ""
        },
        {
            "id": 10,
            "question": "To solve the roots of the equation f(x)=4x^5-7x^2+8x-2 using simple fixed point iteration and initial value of x = 0.5 , which of the following formulations is converging?",
            "options": [
                {
                    "a" : "x=4x^5-7x^2+9x-2",
                    "b" : "x=((7x^2-8x+2)/4)^(1/5)",
                    "c" : "x=(7x^2-8x+2)/x^4",
                    "d" : "x=((4x^5-7x^2-2)/(-8)",
                    "e" : "None of the above",
                }
            ],
            "answer": "x=(7x^2-8x+2)/x^4",
            "score": 0,
            "status": ""
        },
        {
            "id": 11,
            "question": "User requirements are typically stated in natural language.",
            "options": [
                {
                    "a" : "True",
                    "b" : "False",
                }
            ],
            "answer": "True",
            "score": 0,
            "status": ""
        },
        {
            "id": 12,
            "question": "Software is abstracted and intangible.",
            "options": [
                {
                    "a" : "True",
                    "b" : "False",
                }
            ],
            "answer": "True",
            "score": 0,
            "status": ""
        },
        {
            "id": 13,
            "question": "Based on the transformation of a mathematical specification through different representations to an executable program.",
            "options": [
                {
                    "a" : "True",
                    "b" : "False",
                }
            ],
            "answer": "True",
            "score": 0,
            "status": ""
        },
        {
            "id": 14,
            "question": "Transformations are ‘Cleanroom’ so it is straightforward to show that the program conforms to its specification.",
            "options": [
                {
                    "a" : "True",
                    "b" : "False",
                }
            ],
            "answer": "False",
            "score": 0,
            "status": ""
        },
        {
            "id": 15,
            "question": "Based on the idea of manufacturing semiconductors in a “cleanroom environment”.",
            "options": [
                {
                    "a" : "True",
                    "b" : "False",
                }
            ],
            "answer": "True",
            "score": 0,
            "status": ""
        },
        {
            "id": 16,
            "question": "Communication focuses on unit tests (written before the code is made) and running periodic integration tests; functional tests are conducted based on the “user stories”; programmers and customers get concrete feedback.",
            "options": [
                {
                    "a" : "True",
                    "b" : "False",
                }
            ],
            "answer": "False",
            "score": 0,
            "status": ""
        },
        {
            "id": 17,
            "question": "Feedback favors simple designs, common metaphors, collaboration of users and programmers, frequent verbal communication, and feedback.",
            "options": [
                {
                    "a" : "True",
                    "b" : "False",
                }
            ],
            "answer": "False",
            "score": 0,
            "status": ""
        },
        {
            "id": 18,
            "question": "Courage code for today and not tomorrow; refactoring; persistence; knowing when to throw code away.",
            "options": [
                {
                    "a" : "True",
                    "b" : "False",
                }
            ],
            "answer": "True",
            "score": 0,
            "status": ""
        },
        {
            "id": 19,
            "question": "Black Box shows data implementation but hides process implementation; describes how \"state\" information is transformed.",
            "options": [
                {
                    "a" : "True",
                    "b" : "False",
                }
            ],
            "answer": "False",
            "score": 0,
            "status": ""
        },
        {
            "id": 20,
            "question": "Clear Box hides data implementation and process implementation. It describes how a system responds to stimuli, usually in a formal specification language.",
            "options": [
                {
                    "a" : "True",
                    "b" : "False",
                }
            ],
            "answer": "False",
            "score": 0,
            "status": ""
        },

    ]
}
var quizApp = function () {
    this.score = 0;
    this.qno = 1;
    this.currentque = 0;
    var totalque = quiz.JS.length;
    this.displayQuiz = function (cque) {
        this.currentque = cque;
        if (this.currentque < totalque) {
            $("#tque").html(totalque);
            $("#previous").attr("disabled", false);
            $("#next").attr("disabled", false);
            $("#qid").html(quiz.JS[this.currentque].id + '.');
            $("#question").html(quiz.JS[this.currentque].question);
            $("#question-options").html("");
            for (var key in quiz.JS[this.currentque].options[0]) {
                if (quiz.JS[this.currentque].options[0].hasOwnProperty(key)) {
                    $("#question-options").append(
                        "<div class='form-check option-block'>" +
                        "<label class='form-check-label'>" +
                        "<input type='radio' class='form-check-input' name='option' id='q" + key + "' value='" + quiz.JS[this.currentque].options[0][key] + "'><span id='optionval'>" +
                        quiz.JS[this.currentque].options[0][key] +
                        "</span></label>"
                    );
                }
            }
        }
        if (this.currentque <= 0) {
            $("#previous").attr("disabled", true);
        }
        if (this.currentque >= totalque) {
            $('#next').attr('disabled', true);
            for (var i = 0; i < totalque; i++) {
                this.score = this.score + quiz.JS[i].score;
            }
            return this.showResult(this.score);
        }
    }
    this.showResult = function (scr) {
        $("#result").addClass('result');
        $("#result").html("<h1 class='res-header'>Total Score: &nbsp;" + scr + '/' + totalque + "</h1>");
        for (var j = 0; j < totalque; j++) {
            var res;
            if (quiz.JS[j].score == 0) {
                res = '<span class="wrong">' + quiz.JS[j].score + '</span><i class="fa fa-remove c-wrong"></i>';
            } else {
                res = '<span class="correct">' + quiz.JS[j].score + '</span><i class="fa fa-check c-correct"></i>';
            }
            $("#result").append(
                '<div class="result-question"><span>Q ' + quiz.JS[j].id + '</span> &nbsp;' + quiz.JS[j].question + '</div>' +
                '<div><b>Correct answer:</b> &nbsp;' + quiz.JS[j].answer + '</div>' +
                '<div class="last-row"><b>Score:</b> &nbsp;' + res +
                '</div>'
            );
        }
    }
    this.checkAnswer = function (option) {
        var answer = quiz.JS[this.currentque].answer;
        option = option.replace(/</g, "&lt;") //for <
        option = option.replace(/>/g, "&gt;") //for >
        option = option.replace(/"/g, "&quot;")
        if (option == quiz.JS[this.currentque].answer) {
            if (quiz.JS[this.currentque].score == "") {
                quiz.JS[this.currentque].score = 1;
                quiz.JS[this.currentque].status = "correct";
            }
        } else {
            quiz.JS[this.currentque].status = "wrong";
        }
    }
    this.changeQuestion = function (cque) {
        this.currentque = this.currentque + cque;
        this.displayQuiz(this.currentque);
    }
}
var jsq = new quizApp();
var selectedopt;
$(document).ready(function () {
    jsq.displayQuiz(0);
    $('#question-options').on('change', 'input[type=radio][name=option]', function (e) {
//var radio = $(this).find('input:radio');
        $(this).prop("checked", true);
        selectedopt = $(this).val();
    });
});
$('#next').click(function (e) {
    e.preventDefault();
    if (selectedopt) {
        jsq.checkAnswer(selectedopt);
    }
    jsq.changeQuestion(1);
});
$('#previous').click(function (e) {
    e.preventDefault();
    if (selectedopt) {
        jsq.checkAnswer(selectedopt);
    }
    jsq.changeQuestion(-1);
});